<!doctype html>
<html>
  <head>
    <meta charset="utf-8" />
    <meta http-equiv='X-UA-Compatible' content='IE=edge;chrome=1' />
    <title>Rachael Salter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="application/atom+xml" title="Atom Feed" href="/blog/feed.xml" />
    <link href="/stylesheets/all.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
    <link href="/stylesheets/normalize.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
    <link href="/stylesheets/bootstrap-social.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" />
    <script src="/javascripts/all.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="main" role="main">
      <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-08-27T12:44:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>My Path to Web Development Part 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2015/08/27/my-path-to-web-development-part-2.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2015/08/27/my-path-to-web-development-part-2.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-27T12:44:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-27T12:57:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was now tasked at figuring out what I wanted to do with my life and choosing a new major. 
I dabbled in Policy Studies during second semester but had to finally admit that I wasn’t really “political”. Sophomore year had now arrived and I still unsure of what path to take. Then one day I had an epiphany. When I wanted to become an interior designer I always imagined having my own design firm or opening a high-end furniture store. As a child I convinced my friends to help me set up a cookie stand at the entrance of our apartment complex. I launched ‘Rachael’s Cleaning Service’ in my home and posted my prices on the inside of our front door. Yes, I tried to charge my mom for doing chores. I had the blood of an entrepreneur! I immediately felt a rush of rejuvenation and basked in that moment of clarity. Wait, you can major in Entrepreneurship? Yep, and Syracuse had a top ranked program. Ironically, I purposely had not applied to any design specific universities in case I changed my mind (which I didn’t think I would). The stars seemed to have finally aligned, and I concluded that the even younger me wasn’t completely clueless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I transferred into the School of Management and began my study of business. I wasn’t able to take Entrepreneurship classes until Wait, you can major in Entrepreneurship? Junior year because I had to complete core business classes first, but once I settled into my major I loved it! One of my favorite classes was Entrepreneurship &amp;amp; Digital Marketing. This is when my interest it the web was re-born.  A lot had happened between 2003 and 2006. Facebook was launched in 2004 and Mark Zuckerberg was a Rockstar. That same year Google went public and Web 2.0 was THE buzzword. The web evolved into a space for user-generated content and websites became web applications. Everyone was trying to figure out how they could capitalize on it. I learned about SEO, Google Analytics and why it all mattered. I was very interested in this aspect marketing. I also finally revisited coding. I was a member of the campus gospel choir, BCCE, and ran for the position of Historian partly because the duties included maintaining the website. In order to prepare for the position I signed up an Intro to HTML class and attended workshops on Dreamweaver and FrontPage. Oh 2006. I remembered how awesome coding was I was grateful for the opportunity to receive formal training. I rocked as Historian and maintained the website for 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I graduated in 2007 with an interest in digital marking and starting a tech company. My first job was as an Admissions Rep (sales) for a computer training school. Sales was good experience but not exactly my forte so in 2008 I relocated from my hometown in Delaware to Washington, DC in search of new opportunities. In 2008 the recession hit and my main source of income was temp work. This was a hard time. I had to hustle to make ends meet but I believed that things would get better. They did and in 2009 I started work as Market Intelligence Analyst for a consulting firm supplying to research to help companies obtain government contracts. On the side I continued to learn more about web design and entrepreneurship. I taught myself how to build sites with WordPress and was always brainstorming business ideas. I continued my career in marketing and eventually moved back to Delaware and obtained a position an Analyst specializing in email marketing. By this time the web was changing again and the mobile revolution was in full effect. Mobile websites vs. responsive web design was a hot topic and I thought about how I could capitalize. There were new platforms being for creating for starting stand-alone mobile websites…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Path to Web Development Part 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2015/08/27/my-path-to-web-development-part-1.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2015/08/27/my-path-to-web-development-part-1.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-27T12:39:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-27T12:58:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my story. It all started in 2003 during my Freshman year of college at Syracuse University. Although I had grown up with computers we didn’t own one in our home, so as a going away present my family came together and purchased my first computer. It was a HP Desktop that I named Connor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I usually used the computer at school or the library (nerd), I had no idea about and the budding world of social networking. The first one I discovered was BlackPlanet, a very popular online community for African Americans. It had been around since 1999 and was one of a handful of niche sites at the time such as AsianAvenue, MiGente and Friendster. But, in addition to meeting new people, you could customize your profile page with this coding language called HTML. I was hooked! There were some really nice pages and I wanted mine to have a fighting chance. I remember being obsessed with working on my page and hoping the glare from my monitor in our little box dorm didn’t disturb my sleeping roommate. I would be up all hours learning about tags, links and not understanding the purpose of CSS. The &lt;font&gt; tag was awesome! Oh 2003. Coincidently, that was the year MySpace launched, and I was suddenly in the know (yay)! MySpace customizations became a big thing, and I found that I really enjoyed coding. It was exciting to have an idea, figure out how to execute it and have it live for the word to see. 
However, as I became more immersed into my studies coding took a back seat. Although I loved it, it just didn’t cross my mind as something I could do as a career. My dream was to become an interior designer, and I was enrolled in the School of Visual &amp;amp; Performing Arts. I didn’t know of anyone who was a web designer or computer programmer and until my experience with coding on social networking sites, I had never even given thought to how the web worked.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, after one semester of classes my world was turned upside-down. I decided that interior design was not for me. I enjoyed it as hobby but as a career I felt something was missing. I was lost; I wanted to be an interior designer since I was in the 6th grade. A Freshman changing majors can be likened to …. College is the time to explore your interests, let your intellectual curiosities run free, but at the time I remember hating that I didn’t know what direction to take. I  worked hard in high school and received an academic Deans’ Scholarship. I wanted to study, graduate, get a great job and live happily ever after. That’s how it’s supposed to happen, right? Oh If I could go back in time I would tell my younger self that the path to rewarding career is seldom linear. It ended up taking about 9 years from that point to arrive at Web Development…. But I am getting ahead of myself so let’s get back to the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/blog/2015/08/27/my-path-to-web-development-part-2.html"&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>

    </div>
  </body>
</html>